Finding Aid for the Andrew Dowdy Collection of Material about John F. Kennedy LSC.1118
UCLA Library Special Collections
Andrew Dowdy collection of material about John F. Kennedy
circa 1959-1969
UCLA Library Special Collections
Dowdy, Andrew Hunter
LSC.1118
8 boxes (4.0 linear feet)
6 oversize boxes
Andrew Dowdy (b.1904) was the chairman and professor of the Department of Radiology, and one of the five original founders of the School of Medicine at the UCLA. John F. Kennedy (1917-1963) started as a Democratic Congressman from the Boston area, went on to the Senate in 1953, and was elected the 35th President of the U.S. in 1961. He was killed in Dallas, Texas, November 22, 1963. The collection consists primarily of miscellaneous magazines, books, memorabilia, and ephemera related to the life and presidential administration of John F. Kennedy, and materials about members of the Kennedy family, including Robert Kennedy.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Dr. Andrew H. Dowdy, 1972.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942329523606533
Biography
Dowdy was born in Missouri, November 24, 1904; chairman and professor of the Department of Radiology and one of the five original founders of the School of Medicine at the UCLA.
Kennedy was born in Brookline, Massachusetts, May 29, 1917; graduated from Harvard (1940) and entered the Navy; started as a Democratic Congressman from the Boston area and went on to the Senate in 1953; married Jacqueline Bouvier, September 12, 1953; wrote Profiles in courage (1955) and won the Pulitzer Prize in history; Kennedy was elected the 35th President of the U.S. in 1961; the youngest man elected President, he was killed in Dallas, Texas, November 22, 1963.
Scope and Content
Collection consists primarily of miscellaneous magazines, books, memorabilia, and ephemera related to the life and presidential administration of John F. Kennedy. Also includes materials about members of the Kennedy family including Robert Kennedy.
Periodicals.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald)
- [Material re John F. Kennedy]
  - Miscellaneous Magazines, 1960-1968
    - July 1960-September 1966. (Box 1)
    - October 1966-July 1968. (Box 2)
  - [Miscellaneous Books and Ephemera, ], n.d. and 1964
    - Bibliography, medical articles, photographs, and recordings. (Box 2)
    - Books re assasination. (Box 5)
      Scope and Contents note
      Included: An Editorial History of the Administration of President Kennedy 1960-1964, Oral History Program, University of California, Los Angeles.
    - Ephemera re assassination. (Box 6)
      Includes material on Oswald, Ruby, the Warren Report, the Manchester book, and miscellaneous items.
    - Paperback books re President Kennedy's assassination. (Box 7)
    - President Kennedy's Inaugural Address, and ephemera. (Box 7)
  - [Photo News Magazines re the Life and Administration of JFK, ], 1959-1970
    - Esquire Magazine: (miscellaneous issues) and, April 1959-April 1967 May 1967-June 1967. (Box 9)
    - Life Magazine: (miscellaneous issues)., June 18, 1963-August 7, 1970 (Box 10)
    - Look Magazine: (miscellaneous issues)., January 2, 1962-November 26, 1968; March 4, 1969-August 10, 1971 (Box 11, Box 12)
    - Los Angeles Times West Magazine:, November 27, 1966; December 4, 1966; March 6, 1967. (Box 12)
    - McCall's:, July 1966, August 1966. (Box 12)
    - Parade:, December 4, 1966. (Box 12)
    - Paris Match:, November 26, 1966; December 3, 1966. (Box 12)
    - Saturday Evening Post: (miscellaneous issues)., May 6, 1967-December 2, 1967 (Box 12)
    - Show:, April 1963. (Box 12)
    - This Week Magazine:, January 19, 1964. (Box 12)
    - JFK Coloring Book. (Box 12)
  - Newspapers, 1963-1970. (Box 14)
    Primarily the New York Review of Books.
- [Material re Robert Kennedy], 1963-1970
  - Books, Newspapers and Ephemera
    - Books about Robert Kennedy, Sirhan trial transcript, memorial publication, and ephemera. (Box 3)
    - Newspapers, 1963-1970. (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous Magazines, 1966-1969
    - [No titles given], September 1966-September 1968. (Box 3)
    - Dell:, May 1968. (Box 13)
    - Esquire Magazine:, March 1963; July and November 1968. (Box 13)
    - Life Magazine:, July 3, 1964; April 9, 1965. (Box 13)
    - Look Magazine: (miscellaneous issues)., April 16, 1968-December 2, 1968 (Box 13)
    - Los Angeles Times Advertisement Supplement:, August 8, 1968. (Box 13)
    - Los Angeles Times West Magazine:, June 1 and 8, 1969. (Box 13)
    - McCall's:, November 1968. (Box 13)
- [Material re Members of the Kennedy Family]
  - Miscellaneous magazines, 1966-1969. (Box 4)
  - Books, ephemera. (Box 4)
  - Memorabilia and ephemera. (Box 8)